export const LITERATUREINENGLISHA2021 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Something a character says on stage that is meant for the audience alone is:",
A: "An epilogue",
B: "A mime",
C: "A soliloquy",
D: "An aside",
answer: "D. An aside",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A pause within a line of poetry is:",
A: "An alliteration",
B: "A caesura",
C: "A meter",
D: "An assonance",
answer: "B. A caesura",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A recurring idea, image, or a group of images that unifies a work of literature is:",
A: "Motif",
B: "Allusion",
C: "Legend",
D: "Anecdote",
answer: "A. Motif",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. When you are old and grey and full of sleep. The rhythmic pattern of the above line is:",
A: "Anapestic",
B: "Dactylic",
C: "Trochaic",
D: "Iambic",
answer: "D. Iambic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. An inscription on a tombstone is an:",
A: "Epitaph",
B: "Epistle",
C: "Epigram",
D: "Ode",
answer: "A. Epitaph",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. A three-line stanza, rhymed ABA, BCB, CDC is:",
A: "Couplet",
B: "Haiku",
C: "Terzarima",
D: "Heroic couplet",
answer: "C. Terzarima",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The chorus normally features prominently in:",
A: "Poetry",
B: "The epic",
C: "The novel",
D: "Drama",
answer: "D. Drama",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A story which explains a natural phenomenon or justifies the beliefs of a society is:",
A: "Myth",
B: "Legend",
C: "Motif",
D: "Fable",
answer: "A. Myth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The dominant literary device is:",
A: "The Epithet",
B: "The rhetorical question",
C: "Verbal Irony",
D: "Paradox",
answer: "B. The rhetorical question",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Does it stink like rotten meat? Makes use of the sense of:",
A: "Taste",
B: "Touch",
C: "Sight",
D: "Smell",
answer: "D. Smell",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The mood of the poem is one of:",
A: "Joy",
B: "Doubt",
C: "Anger",
D: "Certainty",
answer: "C. Anger",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. A short play performed in the pause between the act of a longer play is:",
A: "Denouement",
B: "Interlude",
C: "Prologue",
D: "Epilogue",
answer: "B. Interlude",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The most intense part of a conflict is the:",
A: "Resolution",
B: "Climax",
C: "Denouement",
D: "Deus ex machina",
answer: "B. Climax",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. I feel a million times better than I felt yesterday is:",
A: "An apostrophe",
B: "A euphemism",
C: "An irony",
D: "A hyperbole",
answer: "D. Hyperbole",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Identify the odd item",
A: "Third person narrative",
B: "Literary appreciation",
C: "First person narrative",
D: "Epistolary technique",
answer: "B. Literary appreciation (The others are related to storytelling)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. A dramatist is someone who …………… plays",
A: "Writes",
B: "Directs",
C: "Commissions",
D: "Promotes",
answer: "A. Writes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Nando’s family lives within the lower income bracket illustrates:",
A: "Sarcasm",
B: "Allusion",
C: "Climax",
D: "Euphemism",
answer: "D. Euphemism (Softening the reality of poverty)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A dramatic performance without words is:",
A: "A mime",
B: "An aside",
C: "A monologue",
D: "A soliloquy",
answer: "A. A mime",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Utopia is a term used to describe:",
A: "Strange circumstances",
B: "Difficulty Conditions",
C: "Pleasant feelings",
D: "Ideal societies",
answer: "D. Ideal societies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The lawyer addressed the bench illustrates:",
A: "Simile",
B: "Oxymoron",
C: "Alliteration",
D: "Metonymy",
answer: "D. Metonymy (Bench represents the judge)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The dominant feeling in the passage is that of:",
A: "Nostalgia",
B: "Anger",
C: "Expectancy",
D: "Fear",
answer: "C. Expectancy (Waiting for his mother's response, anticipating the future)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The feeling is conveyed by the:",
A: "Mouldings on the door",
B: "Boys’ actions",
C: "Tender care of his mother",
D: "Little girl’s taunts",
answer: "B. Boys’ actions (Describing the violent and disturbing behavior)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The dominant literary device in the passage is:",
A: "Personification",
B: "Antithesis",
C: "Litotes",
D: "Parallelism",
answer: "D. Parallelism (Repetition of similar sentence structures)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. …and he had rushed at them, scattering them as some shrieked and some laughed illustrates",
A: "Onomatopoeia",
B: "Climax",
C: "Metaphor",
D: "Metonymy",
answer: "C. Metaphor (Comparing the children scattering to something being scattered)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The main character is:",
A: "Playful",
B: "Inquisitive",
C: "Sad",
D: "Humorous",
answer: "B. Inquisitive (Constantly asking his mother about the world)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The poem is about:",
A: "Debtors",
B: "Dreams",
C: "Costumes",
D: "Appearances",
answer: "D. Appearances",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The poet’s tone is:",
A: "Supplicatory",
B: "Defiant",
C: "Conciliatory",
D: "Complaint",
answer: "D. Complaint (Expressing sadness and oppression)",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The rhyme scheme of the first stanza is:",
A: "aabcc",
B: "ababa",
C: "aabbc",
D: "abbac",
answer: "B. ababa",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The dominant mood is one of:",
A: "Sadness",
B: "Fear",
C: "Joy",
D: "Optimism",
answer: "A. Sadness",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. We wear the mask that grins and lies illustrates",
A: "Irony",
B: "Personification",
C: "Synecdoche",
D: "Alliteration",
answer: "A. Irony (Smiling while inwardly suffering)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Speaker X is",
A: "Hernia",
B: "Philostrate",
C: "Demetrius",
D: "Lysander",
answer: "C. Demetrius",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Speaker Y is",
A: "Titania",
B: "Peaseblossom",
C: "Hippolyta",
D: "Helena",
answer: "D. Helena",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Speaker X sees Speaker Y",
A: "As a pretender",
B: "As a past lover",
C: "For the first time",
D: "For the last time",
answer: "A. As a pretender (He doubts her sincerity)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Both speakers are in the woods",
A: "To hide from each other",
B: "To spy on each other",
C: "For different reasons",
D: "For the same reason",
answer: "C. For different reasons (Helena is lovesick, Demetrius is under a spell)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Night evolves in the speakers’",
A: "Huge responsibilities",
B: "Contrasting feelings",
C: "Despairing thoughts",
D: "Erotic feelings",
answer: "B. Contrasting feelings (Demetrius is suspicious, Helena is enamored)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The speaker is",
A: "Bottom",
B: "Peaseblossom",
C: "Quince",
D: "Puck",
answer: "C. Quince",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The speaker is addressing",
A: "Artists",
B: "Painters",
C: "Actors",
D: "Writers",
answer: "C. Actors",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. They intend to rehearse the play",
A: "A Midsummer Night’s Dream",
B: "Pyramus and Thisbe",
C: "The Tragedy of Lovers",
D: "The Battle Royal",
answer: "B. Pyramus and Thisbe",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The rehearsal is in preparation for",
A: "Egeus’ acceptance of Lysander",
B: "The dance of the fairies",
C: "Theseus’ wedding",
D: "Titania waking up from a dream",
answer: "C. Theseus’ wedding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The main actors will be",
A: "Snug and Snout",
B: "Philostrate and Starveling",
C: "Puck and Mustard seed",
D: "Quince and Bottom",
answer: "D. Quince and Bottom",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Speaker X is",
A: "Titania",
B: "Hippolyta",
C: "Snout",
D: "Oberon",
answer: "A. Titania",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Speaker X has just",
A: "Escaped from the city",
B: "Fallen into a world of dreams",
C: "Woken up from an induced sleep",
D: "Abandoned a loved one",
answer: "C. Woken up from an induced sleep",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Speaker Y is",
A: "Quince",
B: "Lysander",
C: "Demetrius",
D: "Bottom",
answer: "D. Bottom",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Speaker Y is a member of",
A: "Theseus’ retinue",
B: "Titania’s retinue",
C: "The group of actors",
D: "The group of lovers",
answer: "C. The group of actors",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Speaker X’s speech can be described as a",
A: "Satire",
B: "Conceit",
C: "Paradox",
D: "Parody",
answer: "B. Conceit (An elaborate and fanciful comparison)",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The speaker is",
A: "Flute",
B: "Quince",
C: "Bottom",
D: "Philostrate",
answer: "C. Bottom",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The speech is part of the",
A: "Prologue",
B: "Epilogue",
C: "Exposition",
D: "Lyric",
answer: "A. Prologue",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The speaker is involved in putting on",
A: "A scene",
B: "A skit",
C: "An act",
D: "A play",
answer: "D. A play",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The occasion is",
A: "The celebration of the royal marriage",
B: "The king’s decision to banish Hermia",
C: "Oberon’s threat to punish Titania",
D: "Titania falling in love with Bottom",
answer: "A. The celebration of the royal marriage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The speech is",
A: "Romantic",
B: "Satiric",
C: "Comic",
D: "Tragic",
answer: "C. Comic (They are trying to be serious but are inherently funny)",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]